<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>VAST | Visualization &amp; Analysis Systems Technologies</title><link>https://vast.ucar.edu/</link><description>Recent content on VAST | Visualization &amp; Analysis Systems Technologies</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 09:25:32 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vast.ucar.edu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>VAPOR in Nature</title><link>https://vast.ucar.edu/news/20231120-mininni-nature/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 09:25:32 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://vast.ucar.edu/news/20231120-mininni-nature/</guid><description>This month long-time VAPOR collaborator and advisor Pablo Mininni, University of Buenos Aires, published this exciting article on volcanic lightning in Nature. Mininni et al used VAPOR to visualize millions of simulated particles that can collide and generate static electricity, which may result in intense volcanic lightning.</description></item><item><title>SC23 Visualization Showcase and an HPCWire award</title><link>https://vast.ucar.edu/news/20231117-sc23/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2023 16:08:02 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://vast.ucar.edu/news/20231117-sc23/</guid><description>The ViSR team had a strong showing in the Visualization Showcase at SC23 this year, the premier conference for High Performance Computing. Two entries from ViSR were accepted into the event, Visualizing the Impact of the Asian Summer Monsoon on the Composition of the Upper Troposphere and Lower Stratosphere, and Visualizing Megafires: How AI Can Be Used to Drive Wildfire Simulations with Better Predictive Skill.</description></item><item><title>Wildfire Visualization</title><link>https://vast.ucar.edu/projects/wildfire-visualization/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2023 11:57:59 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://vast.ucar.edu/projects/wildfire-visualization/</guid><description>Term: 2021 - 2023 Funding source: NSF Partners: NCAR, Northern Arizona University Website: VAPOR VAPOR has been used for years to help communicate new findings in wildfire simulations from codes like WRF-Fire and CAWFE, through 3D visualization.</description></item><item><title>VAPOR takes home Best Visualization award at PEARC23</title><link>https://vast.ucar.edu/news/20230728-pearc23_best_overall_visualization_award/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2023 10:44:38 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://vast.ucar.edu/news/20230728-pearc23_best_overall_visualization_award/</guid><description>Watch the visualization here
Recent visualization work at NCAR&amp;rsquo;s Research Applications Laboratory (RAL) and Computational &amp;amp; Information Systems Laboratory (CISL) has been awarded the Best Overall Visualization award at this year&amp;rsquo;s PEARC23.</description></item><item><title>Project Pythia Cookbook Cook-Off</title><link>https://vast.ucar.edu/news/20230628-projectpythia-cookoff/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 10:51:44 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://vast.ucar.edu/news/20230628-projectpythia-cookoff/</guid><description>One year from when Project Pythia first introduced Cookbooks, NCAR hosted Project Pythia&amp;rsquo;s first &amp;ldquo;Cookbook Cook-Off&amp;rdquo; hackathon.
Pythia Cookbooks provide example end-to-end geoscientific workflows and are an important tool towards reproducible science efforts.</description></item><item><title>GeoCAT and Project Raijin at the ESDS Unstructured Grids Collaborative Work</title><link>https://vast.ucar.edu/news/20230525-esds_unstructured_collab/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2023 09:03:23 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://vast.ucar.edu/news/20230525-esds_unstructured_collab/</guid><description>“Working With Unstructured Grids” was the topic of the first Collaborative Work Time event of NCAR&amp;rsquo;s Earth Systems Data Science Initiative (ESDS) on April 17, 2023.</description></item><item><title>VAST staff presents the latest research in lossy data compression at IPDPS</title><link>https://vast.ucar.edu/news/20230518-sperr-presentation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vast.ucar.edu/news/20230518-sperr-presentation/</guid><description>VAST project scientist Samuel Li presented his latest research on lossy data compression at the 37th IEEE International Parallel &amp;amp; Distributed Processing Symposium, or IPDPS, in St.</description></item><item><title>High resolution ocean eddies in MOM6</title><link>https://vast.ucar.edu/news/20230105-neverworld/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 09:03:23 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://vast.ucar.edu/news/20230105-neverworld/</guid><description>NEVERWORLD2 is a set of four idealized ocean simulations designed to study mesoscale eddies. These simulations were performed with horizontal grid spacings of 1/4°, 1/8°, 1/16°, and 1/32°.</description></item><item><title>Hosted A (Re)Introduction to Earth System Data Science (ESDS) Across NCAR/UCAR/UCP</title><link>https://vast.ucar.edu/news/20221130-esds_event/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 09:03:23 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://vast.ucar.edu/news/20221130-esds_event/</guid><description>NCAR&amp;rsquo;s Earth System Data Science (ESDS) hosted A (Re)Introduction to Earth System Data Science (ESDS) Across NCAR/UCAR/UCP on November 10th and 11th. This event has been a great implementation of hybrid tutorials, discussion forums, and hackathons in NCAR’s Mesa Lab Main Seminar Room and over Google Meet.</description></item><item><title>GeoCAT tutorials</title><link>https://vast.ucar.edu/news/20221129-geocat_tutorials/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 09:03:23 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://vast.ucar.edu/news/20221129-geocat_tutorials/</guid><description>The GeoCAT team has launched &amp;ldquo;GeoCAT Tutorials&amp;rdquo; to provide its community with guided teaching as well as self-taught content.
The tutorial materials can be accessed via GitHub repository; by cloning and setting up a local configuration as described in the repository home, or through Binder environment right away online!</description></item><item><title>Visualizing wildfire data using VAPOR</title><link>https://vast.ucar.edu/news/20221030-wildfire_vapor_visualization/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 10:58:23 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://vast.ucar.edu/news/20221030-wildfire_vapor_visualization/</guid><description>On October 14, 2020, the East Troublesome Wildfire ignited. It burnt 193,812 acres over the course of 48 days. Between October 20-23 the wildfire rapidly intensified, exploding from 18,550 acres to 187,964 acres in size.</description></item><item><title>Earth System Data Science</title><link>https://vast.ucar.edu/projects/esds/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 11:44:13 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://vast.ucar.edu/projects/esds/</guid><description>Term: 2020 - 2023 Website: https://ncar.github.io/esds/ NCAR&amp;rsquo;s Earth System Data Science (ESDS) initiative aims to build a community of technical support for geoscientists by addressing common big data challenges.</description></item><item><title>Project Pythia Hackathon Introduces Cookbooks</title><link>https://vast.ucar.edu/news/20220801-projectpythia-hackathon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 10:51:44 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://vast.ucar.edu/news/20220801-projectpythia-hackathon/</guid><description>Project Pythia expanded its Scientific Python Ecosystem educational content during a successful hackathon with the introduction of Cookbooks.
Members of the Project Pythia team gathered in Boulder, CO and remotely for a hybrid hacakthon in late June 2022 to develop content and infrastructure for a new pillar of our learning resources called &amp;ldquo;Cookbooks.</description></item><item><title>UXarray ready for unstructured grids data analysis!</title><link>https://vast.ucar.edu/news/20220726-uxarray/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 09:03:23 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://vast.ucar.edu/news/20220726-uxarray/</guid><description>Project Raijin realizes the unstructured grids data recognition and analysis through our recently created, open-source, Python-based package, UXarray.
We are thrilled to announce that UXarray has made its official debut in June, 2022 via Conda and PyPI releases.</description></item><item><title>Project Raijin</title><link>https://vast.ucar.edu/projects/raijin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 11:57:54 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://vast.ucar.edu/projects/raijin/</guid><description>Term: 2021 - 2024 Funding source: NSF Partners: NCAR/CGD, Penn State University, Colorado State University, Max-Planck-Institut für Meteorologie Website: https://raijin.ucar.edu/ The goal of this three-year NSF Earth Cube funded effort is to develop open source, Python based tools for the analysis of simulation data sampled on unstructured grids.</description></item><item><title>NCAR-SIA11Y</title><link>https://vast.ucar.edu/projects/ncar-sia11y/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 11:44:13 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://vast.ucar.edu/projects/ncar-sia11y/</guid><description>Term: 2019 - 2022 Funding source: UCAR, Smithsonian Institution Partners: NCAR, Smithsonian National Museum of African American History and Culture Website: coming soon Augmented Reality (AR) technology has been predominantly used to develop applications that visually augment physical spaces.</description></item><item><title>Project Pythia</title><link>https://vast.ucar.edu/projects/pythia/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 11:44:13 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://vast.ucar.edu/projects/pythia/</guid><description>Term: 2020 - 2023 Funding source: NSF Partners: NCAR, Unidata, and University at Albany Website: https://projectpythia.org/ With the support of a three-year NSF Earth Cube award, Project Pythia is a community-driven effort to develop the world’s goto resource for helping geoscientists at any stage of their career learn how to use the Scientific Python Ecosystem to support their data analysis needs.</description></item><item><title>SPERR Compression</title><link>https://vast.ucar.edu/projects/sperr/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 11:44:13 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://vast.ucar.edu/projects/sperr/</guid><description>Term: 2020 - 2023 Funding source: NSF Website: https://github.com/NCAR/SPERR SPERR is a lossy compressor for scientific data (2D or 3D floating-point data, mostly produced by numerical simulations).</description></item><item><title>VizAccess</title><link>https://vast.ucar.edu/projects/vizaccess/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 11:44:13 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://vast.ucar.edu/projects/vizaccess/</guid><description>Term: 2020 - 2021 Funding source: UCAR Presidents Strategic Innovation Fund 2020 Partners: NCAR Website: [coming soon] Accessibility of scientific visualizations for people who are blind/vision impaired (PBVI) is a critically underexplored area in visualization research.</description></item><item><title>Tactile representations of arctic sea ice data</title><link>https://vast.ucar.edu/news/20220624-vizaccess_prototype/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 10:58:23 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://vast.ucar.edu/news/20220624-vizaccess_prototype/</guid><description>Data visualizations are not the only way to communicate scientific insights; 3D printing &amp;amp; laser cutting offer an inclusive, hands-on way to share data. As part of a larger data visualization accessibility project, VAST researchers &amp;amp; educators are developing tactile data representations of arctic sea ice extant.</description></item><item><title>Visualizations of the recent, devastating Marshall fire</title><link>https://vast.ucar.edu/news/20220624-marshall-fire-vis/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 10:58:23 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://vast.ucar.edu/news/20220624-marshall-fire-vis/</guid><description>The most destructive wildfire in Colorado history was ignited on December 30, 2021 and spread quickly to neighborhoods in Superior and Louisville, driven by drought parched vegetation and winds gusting over 100 miles per hour.</description></item><item><title>VAPOR</title><link>https://vast.ucar.edu/software/vapor/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 09:23:51 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://vast.ucar.edu/software/vapor/</guid><description>VAPOR is the Visualization and Analysis Platform for Ocean, Atmosphere, and Solar Researchers. VAPOR provides an interactive 3D visualization environment that can also produce animations and still frame images.</description></item><item><title>GeoCAT</title><link>https://vast.ucar.edu/software/geocat/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 09:23:17 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://vast.ucar.edu/software/geocat/</guid><description>Geoscience Community Analysis Toolkit (GeoCAT), established in 2019, is the project with several software tools developed in Python in order to lead the software engineering efforts of the National Center for Atmospheric Research (NCAR) Computational and Information Systems Lab (CISL)’s “Pivot to Python” initiative.</description></item></channel></rss>