<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>VAST | Visualization and Analysis Software and Technology</title><link>https://ncar.github.io/vast/</link><description>Recent content on VAST | Visualization and Analysis Software and Technology</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 11:44:13 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ncar.github.io/vast/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Earth System Data Science</title><link>https://ncar.github.io/vast/projects/esds/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 11:44:13 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://ncar.github.io/vast/projects/esds/</guid><description>Term: 2020 - 2023 Website: https://ncar.github.io/esds/ NCAR&amp;rsquo;s Earth System Data Science (ESDS) initiative aims to build a community of technical support for geoscientists by addressing common big data challenges.</description></item><item><title>Project Pythia Hackathon Introduces Cookbooks</title><link>https://ncar.github.io/vast/news/projectpythia-hackathon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 10:51:44 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://ncar.github.io/vast/news/projectpythia-hackathon/</guid><description>Project Pythia expanded its Scientific Python Ecosystem educational content during a successful hackathon with the introduction of Cookbooks.
Members of the Project Pythia team gathered in Boudler, CO and remotely for a hybrid hacakthon in late June 2022 to develop content and infrastructure for a new pillar of our learning resources called &amp;ldquo;Cookbooks.</description></item><item><title>UXarray ready for unstructured grids data analysis!</title><link>https://ncar.github.io/vast/news/uxarray/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 09:03:23 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://ncar.github.io/vast/news/uxarray/</guid><description>Project Raijin realizes the unstructured grids data recognition and analysis through our recently created, open-source, Python-based package, UXarray.
We are thrilled to announce that UXarray has made its official debut in June, 2022 via Conda and PyPI releases.</description></item><item><title>Project Raijin</title><link>https://ncar.github.io/vast/projects/raijin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 11:57:54 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://ncar.github.io/vast/projects/raijin/</guid><description>Term: 2021 - 2024 Funding source: NSF Partners: NCAR/CGD, Penn State University, Colorado State University, Max-Planck-Institut für Meteorologie Website: https://raijin.ucar.edu/ The goal of this three-year NSF Earth Cube funded effort is to develop open source, Python based tools for the analysis of simulation data sampled on unstructured grids.</description></item><item><title>NCAR-SIA11Y</title><link>https://ncar.github.io/vast/projects/ncar-sia11y/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 11:44:13 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://ncar.github.io/vast/projects/ncar-sia11y/</guid><description>Term: 2019 - 2022 Funding source: UCAR, Smithsonian Institution Partners: NCAR, Smithsonian National Museum of African American History and Culture Website: coming soon Augmented Reality (AR) technology has been predominantly used to develop applications that visually augment physical spaces.</description></item><item><title>Project Pythia</title><link>https://ncar.github.io/vast/projects/pythia/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 11:44:13 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://ncar.github.io/vast/projects/pythia/</guid><description>Term: 2020 - 2023 Funding source: NSF Partners: NCAR, Unidata, and University at Albany Website: https://projectpythia.org/ With the support of a three-year NSF Earth Cube award, Project Pythia is a community-driven effort to develop the world’s goto resource for helping geoscientists at any stage of their career learn how to use the Scientific Python Ecosystem to support their data analysis needs.</description></item><item><title>SPERR Compression</title><link>https://ncar.github.io/vast/projects/sperr/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 11:44:13 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://ncar.github.io/vast/projects/sperr/</guid><description>Term: 2020 - 2023 Funding source: NSF Website: https://github.com/NCAR/SPERR SPERR is a lossy compressor for scientific data (2D or 3D floating-point data, mostly produced by numerical simulations).</description></item><item><title>VizAccess</title><link>https://ncar.github.io/vast/projects/vizaccess/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 11:44:13 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://ncar.github.io/vast/projects/vizaccess/</guid><description>Term: 2020 - 2021 Funding source: UCAR Presidents Strategic Innovation Fund 2020 Partners: NCAR Website: [coming soon] Accessibility of scientific visualizations for people who are blind/vision impaired (PBVI) is a critically underexplored area in visualization research.</description></item><item><title>Tactile representations of arctic sea ice data</title><link>https://ncar.github.io/vast/news/vizaccess_prototype/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 10:58:23 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://ncar.github.io/vast/news/vizaccess_prototype/</guid><description>Data visualizations are not the only way to communicate scientific insights; 3D printing &amp;amp; laser cutting offer an inclusive, hands-on way to share data. As part of a larger data visualization accessibility project, VAST researchers &amp;amp; educators are developing tactile data representations of arctic sea ice extant.</description></item><item><title>Visualizations of the recent, devastating Marshall fire</title><link>https://ncar.github.io/vast/news/marshall-fire-vis/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 10:58:23 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://ncar.github.io/vast/news/marshall-fire-vis/</guid><description>The most destructive wildfire in Colorado history was ignited on December 30, 2021 and spread quickly to neighborhoods in Superior and Louisville, driven by drought parched vegetation and winds gusting over 100 miles per hour.</description></item><item><title>VAPOR</title><link>https://ncar.github.io/vast/software/vapor/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 09:23:51 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://ncar.github.io/vast/software/vapor/</guid><description>VAPOR is the Visualization and Analysis Platform for Ocean, Atmosphere, and Solar Researchers. VAPOR provides an interactive 3D visualization environment that can also produce animations and still frame images.</description></item><item><title>GeoCAT</title><link>https://ncar.github.io/vast/software/geocat/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 09:23:17 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://ncar.github.io/vast/software/geocat/</guid><description>Geoscience Community Analysis Toolkit (GeoCAT), established in 2019, is the project with several software tools developed in Python in order to lead the software engineering efforts of the National Center for Atmospheric Research (NCAR) Computational and Information Systems Lab (CISL)’s “Pivot to Python” initiative.</description></item></channel></rss>