<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>VAST News on VAST | Visualization and Analysis Software and Technology</title><link>https://vast.ucar.edu/news/</link><description>Recent content in VAST News on VAST | Visualization and Analysis Software and Technology</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 00:00:00 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vast.ucar.edu/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>VAST staff presents the latest research in lossy data compression at IPDPS</title><link>https://vast.ucar.edu/news/20230518-sperr-presentation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vast.ucar.edu/news/20230518-sperr-presentation/</guid><description>VAST project scientist Samuel Li presented his latest research on lossy data compression at the 37th IEEE International Parallel &amp;amp; Distributed Processing Symposium, or IPDPS, in St.</description></item><item><title>High resolution ocean eddies in MOM6</title><link>https://vast.ucar.edu/news/20230105-neverworld/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 09:03:23 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://vast.ucar.edu/news/20230105-neverworld/</guid><description>NEVERWORLD2 is a set of four idealized ocean simulations designed to study mesoscale eddies. These simulations were performed with horizontal grid spacings of 1/4°, 1/8°, 1/16°, and 1/32°.</description></item><item><title>Hosted A (Re)Introduction to Earth System Data Science (ESDS) Across NCAR/UCAR/UCP</title><link>https://vast.ucar.edu/news/20221130-esds_event/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 09:03:23 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://vast.ucar.edu/news/20221130-esds_event/</guid><description>NCAR&amp;rsquo;s Earth System Data Science (ESDS) hosted A (Re)Introduction to Earth System Data Science (ESDS) Across NCAR/UCAR/UCP on November 10th and 11th. This event has been a great implementation of hybrid tutorials, discussion forums, and hackathons in NCAR’s Mesa Lab Main Seminar Room and over Google Meet.</description></item><item><title>GeoCAT tutorials</title><link>https://vast.ucar.edu/news/20221129-geocat_tutorials/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 09:03:23 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://vast.ucar.edu/news/20221129-geocat_tutorials/</guid><description>The GeoCAT team has launched &amp;ldquo;GeoCAT Tutorials&amp;rdquo; to provide its community with guided teaching as well as self-taught content.
The tutorial materials can be accessed via GitHub repository; by cloning and setting up a local configuration as described in the repository home, or through Binder environment right away online!</description></item><item><title>Visualizing wildfire data using VAPOR</title><link>https://vast.ucar.edu/news/20221030-wildfire_vapor_visualization/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 10:58:23 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://vast.ucar.edu/news/20221030-wildfire_vapor_visualization/</guid><description>On October 14, 2020, the East Troublesome Wildfire ignited. It burnt 193,812 acres over the course of 48 days. Between October 20-23 the wildfire rapidly intensified, exploding from 18,550 acres to 187,964 acres in size.</description></item><item><title>Project Pythia Hackathon Introduces Cookbooks</title><link>https://vast.ucar.edu/news/20220801-projectpythia-hackathon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 10:51:44 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://vast.ucar.edu/news/20220801-projectpythia-hackathon/</guid><description>Project Pythia expanded its Scientific Python Ecosystem educational content during a successful hackathon with the introduction of Cookbooks.
Members of the Project Pythia team gathered in Boudler, CO and remotely for a hybrid hacakthon in late June 2022 to develop content and infrastructure for a new pillar of our learning resources called &amp;ldquo;Cookbooks.</description></item><item><title>UXarray ready for unstructured grids data analysis!</title><link>https://vast.ucar.edu/news/20220726-uxarray/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 09:03:23 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://vast.ucar.edu/news/20220726-uxarray/</guid><description>Project Raijin realizes the unstructured grids data recognition and analysis through our recently created, open-source, Python-based package, UXarray.
We are thrilled to announce that UXarray has made its official debut in June, 2022 via Conda and PyPI releases.</description></item><item><title>Tactile representations of arctic sea ice data</title><link>https://vast.ucar.edu/news/20220624-vizaccess_prototype/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 10:58:23 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://vast.ucar.edu/news/20220624-vizaccess_prototype/</guid><description>Data visualizations are not the only way to communicate scientific insights; 3D printing &amp;amp; laser cutting offer an inclusive, hands-on way to share data. As part of a larger data visualization accessibility project, VAST researchers &amp;amp; educators are developing tactile data representations of arctic sea ice extant.</description></item><item><title>Visualizations of the recent, devastating Marshall fire</title><link>https://vast.ucar.edu/news/20220624-marshall-fire-vis/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 10:58:23 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://vast.ucar.edu/news/20220624-marshall-fire-vis/</guid><description>The most destructive wildfire in Colorado history was ignited on December 30, 2021 and spread quickly to neighborhoods in Superior and Louisville, driven by drought parched vegetation and winds gusting over 100 miles per hour.</description></item></channel></rss>